The triumph of the human spirit
Alive is a adventure, drama, history film directed by Frank Marshall.
The amazing true story of a Uruguayan rugby team's plane that crashed in the middle of the Andes mountains, and their immense will to survive and
pull through alive, forced to do anything and everything they could to stay alive on meager rations and through the freezing cold.
Roberto Canessa, played by Josh Hamilton.
Carlitos Páez, played by Bruce Ramsay.
Nando Parrado, played by Ethan Hawke.
Antonio Balbi, played by Vincent Spano.
Antonio Vizintín, played by John Newton.
Gustavo Zerbino, played by David Kriegel.
Alive is a 1993 American survival drama film directed by Frank Marshall, and based on
Piers Paul Read's 1974 book Alive: The Story of the Andes Survivors.
It is the second feature film about the Uruguayan rugby team
whose plane crashed in the Andes mountains in 1972.
Filmed in the Purcell Mountains in British Columbia, the film was written by John Patrick Shanley,  narrated by John Malkovich,  and
stars Ethan Hawke, Josh Hamilton, Vincent Spano, Bruce Ramsay, John Haymes Newton, Illeana Douglas, and Danny Nucci.
One of the survivors, Nando Parrado (portrayed by Hawke in the
film), served as the technical advisor for the film.
Alive was released on January 15, 1993 by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution through the Touchstone Pictures label in the
United States and Canada and by Paramount Pictures through United International Pictures in international markets.
The film received mixed to positive reviews from critics and
grossed $82.5 million on a $32 million budget.
The film explores themes of airplane wreck, based on
true story, rugby, survival, stranded.
The tone is emotional.